J. Vallis-Walker

Web, Salesforce, & Software Developer

LinkedIn | Github | Portfolio

Education

Berkeley Coding Bootcamp

UC Berkeley Extension
JUN 2024 - DEC 2024

Over the course of six months, we learned how to do the following:

- Build front-end websites from scratch, as well as using ready-made frameworks that enable you to build efficiently.
- Create full-stack single-page web applications using RESTful API routes and AJAX methods, and describe how front-end applications communicate with back-end applications and databases.
- Implement structured and unstructured databases to convert static websites into dynamic websites that persist data.
- Build communication skills and demonstrate the foundational computer-science knowledge that is required during technical interviews.
- Apply the accepted and standard basics of social coding—including source control, issue tracking, and functional feedback—as part of a development community, while building an application.
- Demonstrate strong teamwork and project management skills as a collaborator and independent contributor during the development cycle of complex projects.

B.A in Psychology San Jose State University 2010 - 2013

About

Ever since discovering Excel formulas in my first job out of college, building applications has fascinated me. Although I lacked formal training, I quickly learned and became an Apex (Java) Developer after being introduced to the Salesforce ecosystem. I've spent the past 5+ years deepening my understanding of coding principles, and recently completed a Full Stack bootcamp through UC Berkeley Extension. I'm excited to take this next step in my career into the world of web development.

Experience

Salesforce Developer // SambaSafety

AUG 2023 - Present

- Develop Apex for record trigger automations and lwc/action functionality
- Develop python scripts for populating complex CPQ data in sandbox and production environments
- Lead initiative to transition Salesforce org to international currency quoting capability

Salesforce Developer // Lyra Health

OCT 2021 - JAN 2023

- Core member of development and support team (Apex, LWCs, Org-to-Org and Vendor-to-Org integration)
- Developed git/source-control solutions for expanding development team

Salesforce Developer // Making Waves Foundation MAR 2019 - OCT 2021

- Sole member of development and support team (Apex, LWC, declarative programming, Lightning transition)
- Lifecycle management of all Salesforce projects (requirement gathering, development, UAT/QA, and post-launch support)

Salesforce Administrator // Making Waves Foundation SEP 2017 - MAR 2019

- Develop new Salesforce functionality in collaboration with interdepartmental staff via org configuration and declarative programming
- Perform prg maintenance, such as system updates, backups, data import and exports